{"1": {"question": "What does the nocturne's association with night relate to?", "correct": "Being performed in the evenings", "incorrect": ["Theme of the idea of night", "Serving royalty in the ranks of knights", "Being a part of a set of works with other themes such as day"]}, "2": {"question": "When did pieces titled notturno first appear?", "correct": "18th century", "incorrect": ["17th century", "19th century", "20th century"]}, "3": {"question": "Bel Canto, an influence on Chopin, translates to 'beautiful singing'. What did this style place an emphasis on?", "correct": "The beauty of the singing voice and its agility and expressiveness", "incorrect": ["The beauty of the singing voice and its regality and power", "The expressiveness of the singing voice and how it can have a loud and full sound", "The annoying opera sound"]}, "4": {"question": "What form is Chopin's Nocturne no.1 in?", "correct": "Ternary", "incorrect": ["Binary", "Sonata", "Consent"]}, "5": {"question": "Which of the following was a distinctive feature of Chopin's notation of the accompaniment pattern?", "correct": "Complex arrangement of stems", "incorrect": ["Basso continuo", "Rhythmic repetition", "Consecutive fifths and octaves"]}, "6": {"question": "What does the tempo designation in nocturne no.1 (cantabile) mean?", "correct": "'In a singing style'", "incorrect": ["'Like song'", "'Smooth and silky'", "'Cantaloupe' aka rockmelon"]}, "7": {"question": "What does 'semplice e tranquillo' mean?", "correct": "Unaffected and calm", "incorrect": ["Simple and tranquil", "Unaffected and tranquil", "Simple and smooth"]}, "8": {"question": "Who are Chopin's Op. 15 set of nocturnes dedicated to?", "correct": "Ferdinand Hiller", "incorrect": ["Franz Liszt", "Heinrich Heine", "Hector Berlioz"]}, "9": {"question": "The term for the extended embellishment that is seen in nocturne no.2 is fioritura, meaning what?", "correct": "Flowering", "incorrect": ["Finishing", "Grand and forte (loud)", "Fortified"]}, "10": {"question": "When were Chopin's No.15 nocturnes published?", "correct": "1834", "incorrect": ["1843", "1934", "1943"]}, "11": {"question": "Which of the following was NOT a contemporary of Chopin?", "correct": "Franz Schubert", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Felix Mendelssohn", "Cesar Franck"]}, "12": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin?", "correct": "Polish", "incorrect": ["French", "Austrian", "Mongolian"]}, "13": {"question": "What was Chopin's primary instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Violin"]}, "14": {"question": "Which of the three nocturnes is the most elaborate, featuring a highly ornamental line for the right hand?", "correct": "No. 2", "incorrect": ["No. 1", "No. 3", "No. 4"]}, "15": {"question": "All of Chopin's compositions include which instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Harpsichord", "Flute", "Voice"]}, "16": {"question": "In the last 18 years of his life, Chopin gave only 30 public performances, preferring which setting?", "correct": "The salon", "incorrect": ["The chambers", "The concert hall", "The cathedral"]}, "17": {"question": "What nationality was Chopin's father?", "correct": "French", "incorrect": ["Polish", "German", "Warsawian", "Austro-Hungarian"]}, "18": {"question": "Which instrumental genre did Chopin create?", "correct": "The instrumental ballade", "incorrect": ["The polonaise", "The mazurka", "Music with nationalism"]}, "19": {"question": "What instrument did Chopin begin lessons on in 1823?", "correct": "Organ", "incorrect": ["Piano", "Violin", "Flute"]}, "20": {"question": "What did Chopin study at the Warsaw Conservatory?", "correct": "Music theory, figured bass, and composition", "incorrect": ["Music theory, figured bass, and word painting", "Music theory, composition, and performance", "Music theory, performance, and composition"]}, "21": {"question": "Who composed the Nocturne No 5 in Bb major, H 37?", "correct": "John Field", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumann", "Franz Schubert", "Frederic Chopin"]}, "22": {"question": "To what extent was the Italian opera in the 1830s an influence on Chopin?", "correct": "Striking", "incorrect": ["Great", "Moderate", "Little"]}, "23": {"question": "What movement is the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Sonata form", "incorrect": ["Rondo form", "Theme and variations", "Strophic"]}, "24": {"question": "What key is Schumann's Piano Quintet in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Ab major", "Bb major", "Fb major"]}, "25": {"question": "Schumann had not (with one juvenile exception) composed chamber music until what year?", "correct": "1842", "incorrect": ["1840", "1832", "1845"]}, "26": {"question": "What is an obbligato accompaniment?", "correct": "An elaborate and indispensable accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A simple and essential accompaniment", "The melody played in the accompaniment", "An accompaniment obliged to play an accompanying part"]}, "27": {"question": "Prior to 1840, Schumann had only written music for what instrument?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Organ", "Violin", "Voice"]}, "28": {"question": "What is Schumann's Liederjahr?", "correct": "Year of songs", "incorrect": ["Knee-lengths leather breeches", "Setting poetry to classical music", "Lid and jar"]}, "29": {"question": "Where and when did Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 premiere?", "correct": "Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1843", "incorrect": ["Concert hall of the Leipzig Gewandhaus in 1842", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1843", "Concert hall of the Leipzig Kupfersaal in 1842"]}, "30": {"question": "Why is Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 considered a watershed work?", "correct": "It made the Piano and string quartet format the favoured one for Piano quintets", "incorrect": ["It made the Piano and string quartets the disliked format for Piano quintets", "It made the Piano quintet the favoured format", "Because of the flooding in regional NSW"]}, "31": {"question": "Who played piano on Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 in the premiere show?", "correct": "His wife, Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["His father, August Schumann", "His mother, Johanna Christine Schnabel", "His son, Felix Schumann"]}, "32": {"question": "What did Schumann compose in addition to the Quintet in 1842?", "correct": "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "incorrect": ["Four string quartets, a Piano quintet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "Three string quartets, a Piano quartet and a set of Phantasiest端cke", "Three string quartets, two Piano quintets and a set of Phantasiest端cke"]}, "33": {"question": "What did Schumann do in his Liederjahr?", "correct": "Turned his attention almost entirely to writing German songs, or Lieder", "incorrect": ["Reflected on all his life choices", "Turned his attention to writing poetry", "Ate some marmalade"]}, "34": {"question": "What is one feature of Schumann's Quintet that distinguishes it from Classical (e.g. Mozart and Haydn) Sonata form?", "correct": "Tendency towards a continuous texture in which many of the ends of thematic units and cadence points elide with the next thematic unit", "incorrect": ["Tendency to get distracted", "Tendency towards a dense texture in which many of the ends of thematic units end in cadences that have dense voicings", "An extensive use of ornamentation and expressive techniques"]}, "35": {"question": "What key is the first subordinate theme in the exposition of Schumann's Quintet in? ", "correct": "The dominant Bb major", "incorrect": ["The dominant Eb major", "The relative major Bb major", "Eb minor"]}, "36": {"question": "How long is the main theme in Schumann's Quintet?", "correct": "8 bars", "incorrect": ["16 bars", "12 bars", "4 bars"]}, "37": {"question": "Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44 was dedicated to _______ and remained a staple in her repertoire throughout her long pianistic career.", "correct": "Clara Schumann", "incorrect": ["Johanna Christine Schnabel", "Joan Samantha Bach", "Maria Schumann"]}, "38": {"question": "Which section is the least predictable part of the First movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op. 44?", "correct": "Development", "incorrect": ["Exposition", "Recapitulation", "Coda"]}, "39": {"question": "Which instrument is featured in a soloistic role in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Piano", "incorrect": ["Violin", "Viola", "Cello"]}, "40": {"question": "What is the role of the strings section in the development of the first movement of Schumann's Piano Quintet Op.44?", "correct": "Accompaniment", "incorrect": ["Soloistic", "Melodic", "Chairman"]}, "41": {"question": "Which era is Robert Schumann from?", "correct": "Romantic period", "incorrect": ["Classical period", "Baroque period", "Contemporary period"]}, "42": {"question": "Who loved to write proper names such as Abegg, Asch and Bach in musical notation and then use them as themes in his works?", "correct": "Schumann", "incorrect": ["Schubert", "Handel", "Mendelssohn", "Rorschach"]}}